Jeeva R

7200712356 · jeevasmart82@gmail.com · Website - Jeeva LinkedIn - Jeeva

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER

IT Support Engineer with 2 years 3 months of experience providing Level 1 support to users via phone, email, Slack,and portal. Expertise in troubleshooting user desktop setups and remaining calm in difficult situations. Currently employed at Vectra Automation, Inc., where I am responsible for providing all IT support to users, including troubleshooting, Level 1 support, and end-user help desk support. Through my current position, I have honed my skills in delivering end-user help desk support and have developed the ability to remain composed and effective in challenging situations.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Active Directory
Remote Troubleshooting
Technical Support

Global Service Desk Azure AD End User Support Hardware Configuration IT Asset Management User Account Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Vectra Automation, Inc.

Apr 2022 - Present

Information Technology Support Engineer

Accomplishments:

- Managed and deployed corporate PCs/laptops: configured new hardware, performed backups, diagnosed and repaired issues.
- Analyzed, logged, tracked, and resolved user queries concerning User's Desktop setups.
- Monitoring and supporting the infra as well the remote devices in the network.
- Created SSL VPN users within the Fortigate Firewall, L1 Network troubleshooting.
- Maintained and managed G-Suite admin activities, including user email ID creation and monitoring.
- Configured IIS servers for hosting the Nuget server.
- Installed SSL certificates on IIS Servers to ensure secure web services.
- Monitored and provided support for machines accessibility through SSL VPN, TeamViewer or Anydesk.
- Implemented security measures by creating group policies(GPO) to restrict specific permissions on desktops and set folder permissions for users.
- Conducted general IT tasks: onboarded new hires, and diagnosed and repaired end-user devices.
- · Performed and monitored remote server backups (Acronis Image Backup).
- Handled troubleshooting of Active Directory, DNS, and DHCP to maintain networking connectivity.
- Managed endpoint security using McAfee and Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Maintained IT asset data: tracked serial numbers, software keys, and locations.
- Conducted comprehensive system troubleshooting, and documented system events.
- Efficiently coordinated with vendors to resolve vendor-specific issues.
- Coordinated testing, upgrades, and configuration of system files and services.
- Demonstrated a strong knowledge of performance optimization for Windows laptops, including reconfiguration, maintenance, and upgrades.
- Providing extended support to end users and resolving the issues immediately.

Freelancer - Desktop Support

Nov 2018 - Present

Accomplishments:

- 1. System Installation and Configuration:
- Installation of the operating system (OS) and driver updates.
- Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.
- Windows OS installation, formatting, partitioning, configuration, and troubleshooting.
- 2. Hardware and Network Support:
 - Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
 - · ISP routers and switches configuration.
 - Installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of LAN.
- Network administration: Static IP and DHCP configuration.
- · Setting up and sharing network printers.
- · Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.
- 3. Mobile Phones and Security:
 - · Unlocking and flashing of all mobile phones.
 - · Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Linux Tutorial - Great Learning
Google Workspace Administration - LinkedIn
Windows 10 for IT Support - LinkedIn
MacOS Ventura - LinkedIn

EDUCATION

Kings Engineering College

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer science Engineering

Arignar Anna Higher Secondary School

Jun 2015 - May 2017

Higher Secondary School Certificate, Mathematics and Computer Science